Mrs. Jia, we're coming.
宝妈 我们来啦
I'm not breastfeeding.
我不喂奶
I want to wean.
我要断奶
I'm in pain. Get lost.
我疼着呢 抱走
Hmmm.
不是
You're having a fever...
您正发烧呢 应该
No means no.
我说了不要
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文
Coming.
来了
Go.
赶紧走
I'm coming!
来了 来了 来了
What's wrong?
怎么了
Let's find a lactation consultant for her.
给宝妈找个通乳师吧
No need.
找什么通乳师啊
Get lost.
走走走 走
Alright.
好 走走走
Take the baby out
带着孩子出去
and have some formula.
先给她喂奶粉
Okay.
好 好的
Thank you.
辛苦 辛苦 辛苦
Be careful.
慢点啊
Honey.
老婆
Honey, we have to...
老婆 你说咱们
We have to do something.
咱们总得做点什么
You're having a fever.
你这发着烧呢
I want to have a fever.
我就是要发烧
I'm going to turn breast milk into yogurt.
我要把母乳变成酸奶
Who else wants me to feed the baby?
看你们谁让我喂奶
Honey.
老婆
How dare I think that?
我怎么敢这么想呢
I will feel sorry for you.
我 我心疼还来不及呢
Right, honey?
是不老婆
When I was giving birth to Xiongxiong,
生熊熊的时候
I didn't have to worry so much.
就没有那么多事
I said no second child.
我说不要生二胎吧
My chest and stomach hurt.
我胸疼 肚子疼
I know.
我知道 我知道
The scar hurts.
刀疤疼
I know you're hurting.
我知道你疼
My head hurts too.
我头也疼
My heart hurts, honey.
我心比你还疼 老婆
It's uncomfortable.
难受
Alright.
难受 难
I'll call the nurse.
我去叫护士来
Honey, I'll call the nurse.
老婆 我叫护士
Uncomfortable.
难受
Nurse!
护士
This is...
这真是
It's not bad.
还行
It's a recurring fever.
反复地发烧
It doesn't smell bad.
不难闻啊
Lanxiang, what are you doing here?
兰香姐 你怎么来了
I've come to bring Mengxin some food
我来给心心送饭
and some medicine.
还有汤药
Your mom-in-law made it for breastfeeding.
你丈母娘熬的 下奶的
Mom, you're obsessed with breastfeeding.
妈 天天跟下奶较上劲了
She doesn't like that word.
她不爱听那词
Stop saying that.
别老说了
She's got a fever.
你说都发烧了
She's still not breastfeeding.
她还不喂奶啊
Little Watermelon was born prematurely,
咱家小西瓜早产
is physically weak.
身体弱
If we have her formula
你说天天
every day,
给那孩子喝奶粉
She will get inflamed.
多上火呀
Let me tell you that
我告诉你啊
Mengxin has a fever
心心就因为不喂奶
because she doesn't breastfeed.
才发烧的
If she had breastfed,
她要是喂了奶啊
the fever would have gone away.
那烧就退了
Really?
真的吗
Of course.
那肯定的呀
Yes, Mr. Jia.
是的 贾总
Li Jing said,
李静大姐说
that is...
心心那叫
Pain means discomfort.
痛则不通
Pain...
痛
Pain is discomfort; comfort, no pain.
痛则不通 通则不痛
Right.
对对对
Then I'll try it.
那我试试啊
Okay.
好 好
Take it to Mengxin and drink it.
快拿去给心心喝
What's that strange smell?
什么怪味啊
Are you sure this will work?
您确定这能通啊
Yes, it does.
能
Don't move.
你别乱动了啊
Just lie down like this.
就这么平躺着
In two hours,
过两小时
I'll come back to take your temperature.
再来给你测一次体温
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Come on, mom.
来 妈
Honey,
媳妇 媳妇
it's a tonic soup.
大补的汤
It's for my milk again?
又是给我下奶的
Honey,
媳妇
Not at all. I'm telling you that
哪儿是啊 我跟你说
my brother-in-law's brother-in-law
大姐夫的姐夫
is a famous Chinese doctor.
是个特有名的中医
He's given you a prescription.
专门给你开了个方子
This soup is
这味汤是
carefully made.
慢慢炖出来的
My sister said,
大姐说了
Pain is discomfort; comfort, no pain.
通则不痛 痛则不通
As long as you feel comfort,
只要咱通了
you'll be alright, honey.
就不发烧了 媳妇
Forget about the breastfeed.
孩子喂不喂奶再说
Drink it while it's hot,
趁热喝
honey.
宝宝
Drink it.
来
Drink it while it's hot.
趁热喝
It smells so fishy!
好腥啊
What's this?
这什么呀
I won't drink it.
我不喝了
But it's good for you.
好东西
It takes a lot to make it.
很难搞的
Drink it while it's hot.
喝了 趁热喝
It takes a lot to make it.
很难搞 趁热喝
Honey.
老婆
What the hell is this?
这到底是什么
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文
Mom.
妈
It's Chinese medicine.
中药啊
It's very effective.
很管用的
Drink it.
快喝
Chinese medicine. It works.
中药 很管用的
If you don't tell me,
你们要是不说
I won't drink it.
我就不喝
It's very expensive.
很金贵的
It's lumbricus.
是地龙
That's right.
对
Honey.
很金贵 媳妇
Lumbricus.
地龙
What is lumbricus?
地龙是什么
Earthworm.
蚯蚓哪
Mom.
妈
Let's get out of here.
咱出去吧
Let's go.
妈 快快快 快
What?
这
Mom.
妈 妈 妈 妈
You blow me away.
我服您了
Just let her drink.
你让她喝就完了
Why did you tell her so much?
你跟她说那么多干吗
Saying lumbricus all that.
什么地龙不地龙的
It's you asking me.
那你问我呢
That's why
我 我
I said.
那我才说
This is good stuff.
这 这是好东西
Haowen.
浩文
Ma'am.
阿姨
Meng'an.
大姐
You're here.
你可来了
How's Mengxin?
心心怎么样了
Sister.
姐
I'm just trying to be nice.
你说我也是好心
I saw that
我看到心心
she was suffering from a fever.
发烧难受得厉害
I asked Li Jing
我就让李静
to give her this prescription.
给开的这个秘方
You don't have to make it clear to her
关键您告诉她
that this was made with earthworms.
这是拿蚯蚓熬的
It's normal
这中药里头有
to find some insects
有点虫子
in traditional Chinese medicine,
不挺正常吗
like centipedes,
什么 蜈蚣啊
scorpions,
蝎子啊
or earthworms.
你说地龙啊
Don't worry,
那个
Ma'am.
阿姨
Just leave it all
没事
to me.
都交给我
She has been working hard.
阿姨也挺辛苦的
Why don't you take her home to rest?
你送她回去休息休息
And you should go and freshen up as well.
你也回去拾掇拾掇自己
I've
那个
got this covered.
这儿有我呢
Don't worry.
您就放心吧
Sister,
是 姐
I feel assured with you here.
您来我就放心了
What about this?
那 那 这个
I will
交给我
take care
来
of everything.
都交给我
Thank you so much for coming.
大姐 真是太感谢你了
No problem.
没事
Don't be upset.
别生气了
They're all gone now.
他们都走了
All gone?
都走了
Including Jia Haowen?
贾浩文也走了
Bring him back.
让他回来
I was the one who told him to leave.
我让他走的
Just let him go home
你让他也回去
and freshen up.
洗一洗 涮一涮
Am I right?
是不是
Won't you feel better
看见一个
seeing a clean and handsome husband
干净帅气的老公在跟前
by your side?
你心情不愉悦吗
He's been taking care
人家也衣不解带的
of you non-stop for days.
照顾你好几天了
He needs a break too.
让他缓缓吧
Is it his child?
这孩子是不是他要生的
Why should he have it easy
凭什么他轻轻松松
while I suffer through childbirth?
回家享清闲去了
Isn't it your child
那这孩子不是也
too?
是你生的吗
And Haowen still needs to help raise it.
老贾还得养孩子呢
Raising a child isn't
养孩子
as hard as giving birth.
有我生孩子苦吗
I went through so much pain
我生孩子
to have this baby.
遭了多大的罪啊
And now he just gets
他倒好
to be a dad like that?
这么容易就当爹
No way.
不行
Do you know
你知道吗
what his family did
他们家人
to make me
为了让我下奶
produce more milk?
当一个合格的奶牛
They forced me to drink earthworm soup!
用活蚯蚓煮汤给我喝
Earthworms,
蚯蚓啊
alive
活的
and with dirt on them.
带着泥呢
Disgusting.
恶心
You see it?
你看见了
No.
没有
That's right.
不就完了吗
Rumors start like this.
谣言就是这么起的
This recipe was
你这 这方子
probably prescribed
应该是我姐夫
by my brother-in-law.
给开的方子
If there were earthworms,
要说有蚯蚓
they would have been dried ones.
那也是蚯蚓干
But dried earthworms
那干蚯蚓
are still earthworms.
它也是蚯蚓呀
I've had this medicine
其实这药吧
before too.
姐也喝过的
What?
你也喝过
How could you drink it?
你怎么喝得下去啊
When I had engorged breasts,
那个时候涨奶呀
it hurt so much.
它疼啊
I'm telling you
我跟你说
At that time,
那个时候疼得我
I was willing to do anything
别说喝中药了
just to stop the pain,
只要你不让我疼
even drink Chinese medicine.
你让我干什么都行
And you know
但你知道喝完之后
what happened?
效果怎么样吗
No more engorgement,
什么涨奶呀
no mastitis,
乳腺炎呀
nothing.
不存在
No symptoms at all,
没感觉
you see?
知道吗
That amazing, huh?
这么神奇啊
You bet.
那你以为呢
Want to try it?
要不要试试
No way.
我不试
I'd rather let it swell.
我就让它涨着
They're just trying
他们就是
to turn me into a milk cow,
让我下奶当奶牛
feeding the baby my milk.
给孩子喂奶
I'm not doing it.
我不喂奶
That' right.
不喂
No need to breastfeed.
谁喂奶呀
We won't do that.
咱不喂
Why would we need to?
喂什么奶呀
That's what all those
要那么多奶粉厂
formula milk companies
是干吗用的
are for.
让他们选去呗
Am I right?
是不是
But the key is,
关键是
do you want to feel better now?
你现在想不想舒服
It hurts.
我疼
Oh,
疼是吧
this is just
你这才刚开始
the beginning.
你这
There's more pain to come?
还有比这更疼的
Some people even need surgery.
那还有开刀的呢
Really? On the chest?
在胸上开刀啊
Yeah,
那可不
if it gets infected
那发炎了呀
and the tissue gets damaged,
组织结构被破坏了
it has
那不切
to be cut.
怎么整啊
I don't want surgery.
我 我不要切
We won't let it come to that.
不切 咱不切
We have so many things to do.
咱现在不是才刚开始吗
Just drink the medicine
把药喝了
and it might help.
可能就不用了
Will it work after just one dose?
那 喝这一次就管用吗
One dose should
一次
give some relief,
有缓解
and you'll see full effects in seven days.
七天见疗效
Drink it up.
来
It tastes awful.
太难喝了
Yes.
是
I know.
姐知道
But this is
但是
for your comfort.
咱不是为了舒服吗
Pinch your nose, close your eyes,
掐上鼻子 闭上眼睛
and chug it down
一口气
in one go.
把它闷了
Alright,
来
one, two, three, drink!
一 二 三 走
I've never seen
就没见过
such a brave sister!
这么勇敢的妹妹
I'm suffering so much
我这个月子坐得呀
during this postpartum period.
太苦了
Don't cry, my dear.
我妹不哭了啊
I'm here.
姐在呢
They haven't let you
他们是不是好几天
shower or wash your hair in days, right?
都没让你洗澡 洗头了
Yes.
他们不让我洗
The wound can't get wet,
那个咱有刀口不能淋水
or it might get infected.
不然又发炎了
But do you want to wash your hair?
那你想不想洗个头呀
Can I?
我可以洗吗
Just tell me if you want to.
你就说你想不想
I do.
我想
Then let's do it.
那咱就洗
I'll finish the
我晚上就能把这个
client memo tonight
客户备忘录做好
and send it to you once it's done.
做完以后我抄送给你
You're back on your game so quickly,
你状态恢复得真快啊
like the old days
现在已经完全是一副
when you used
当年在职场
to crush me at work.
碾压我时候的样子了
It's all thanks
那还不是因为
to your wise leadership.
你的英明领导
Without your guidance,
没有你的带领
I wouldn't be back
我哪能这么快
to work so soon.
回归职场呢
If you hadn't taken
幸亏你当年
maternity leave back then,
回家生孩子了
you'd be my boss right now,
不然现在你就是我老板
and I'd be here
我在坐在这儿打字
typing reports to you.
向你汇报了
Stop flattering me.
少捧杀我
Just go easy on me
只要在投资策略会上
in the investment strategy meetings.
少骂我几句就行啦
I only criticize the work, not the person.
我那是对事不对人
Don't take it to heart.
别往心里去
Oh, at this time,
这点了
the kids should be getting out of school.
孩子们该放学了吧
Don't let me stop you from picking them up.
别耽误你接孩子
No worries, we have a nanny at home.
没有 家里有阿姨呢
A nanny isn't the same as a mom, is it?
阿姨跟妈妈能一样吗
That doesn't
这话
sound like you.
不像从你嘴里说出来的
What should I
我嘴里应该
be saying then?
说出什么话来
"Chen Wanzhen,
陈婉真
forget about the kids
别管孩子
and go earn money for me!"
给我挣钱去
You really think I'm Zhou Leech.
你真把我当周扒皮了
Alright.
好嘞
How do you feel?
怎么样
Good.
舒服
Good, isn't it?
舒服吧
The old saying is right,
其实老话说得也没错
but they didn't have hair dryers
只是那个时候
back then,
没有吹风机
so letting your hair dry naturally
要是洗完头的话
could lead to
就那么湿着
dampness entering the body.
容易湿寒入体的
But now, even though you've washed it,
但是咱这现在洗了
you shouldn't do it too often.
你也不能老洗
Alright?
知道吗
Feel good after washing my hair.
洗完头心情都跟着舒坦
If you feel good,
你舒坦就好
everyone feels good.
你舒坦全家都舒坦
Why didn't you
你说你为什么
come sooner?
不早点来呀
If you had,
你要是早点来看看我
I'd have
陪陪我
felt better
我这心情
much earlier.
不就早舒坦了吗
That's not fair.
这事可不能赖我啊
You didn't want to see me.
是谁说不想见我来着
Who made
那是谁啊
my husband
鼓捣我老公
sign the surgery consent form,
在手术同意书上签的字
causing me to have a Caesarean
害得我剖腹产
when I wanted a natural birth?
人家本来想顺产的
Naturally born children are smarter.
都说了顺产的孩子聪明
You didn't even want the baby,
你都不想要她了
so why care if she is smart or not?
还管她聪明不聪明
Why don't you just say
自个儿想生
you want to have a baby?
你就说生不就完了吗
Don't be so stubborn.
还老嘴那么硬
You're a grown woman now,
又这么大人了
and if you don't want this baby,
真是怀了孕不想要
you can handle her
你一个人还处理不了
yourself.
一个孩子
Let me see.
我看看
Little Grape.
小葡萄
I'm your auntie.
我是你阿姨
You know the baby's name is Little Grape?
你都知道他叫小葡萄啦
Yunjie told me.
云阶跟我说的呀
Yunjie named the baby Little Grape,
云阶起的小葡萄
Xiongxiong named her Little Watermelon.
熊熊起的小西瓜
A whole family of fruits,
这一家子水果
isn't it fun?
多有意思
So sweet.
甜嘛
It's been three months, right?
这得有三个月了吧
Little Grape is now like a Little Plum.
小葡萄就成小李子了
We can't call it Little Plum.
可不能叫小李子啊
Right,
对对对
Little Grape sounds better.
还是小葡萄好听
Come on, I'll help you back to bed.
行了 我扶你上床吧
Hold the wound, take it slow.
按着点刀口啊 慢点
Here you go.
来
Okay.
行
Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
Mr. Yu.
俞辰叔叔
Play with us.
过来陪我们一起玩
Yeah.
对
I'll just grab my package quickly
我去拿个快递啊
and be right back.
马上回来
Okay.
好吧
Wait for me.
等我啊
Alright.
好
Mr. Zhou,
周总
thanks for sending me back.
谢谢你送我回来啊
Wanzhen.
温蒂
What's wrong?
怎么
I just received this.
我刚收到的
It's Mr. Qian's letter of apology.
这是钱副总的道歉书
You won't be troubled
你以后不会再
by him anymore.
受到困扰了
Thank you, boss.
谢谢老板
Don't mention it.
别跟我客气
I'm not doing this for you.
我并不是为了你
I just don't want this issue
我只是不希望
to affect your ability
这件事影响到
to make money for me.
你为我赚钱
I know,
我知道
but
但是呢
I still appreciate it.
我还是得谢谢你
Sir, your package.
先生 您的快递
Okay.
好嘞
Alright.
好
Thanks.
谢谢啊
What's this?
这是干吗啊
Don't get me wrong.
千万别误会
It's a gift to celebrate your promotion.
这是祝贺你升职的
I know you probably don't have time
我知道你肯定没空
for a celebration dinner with me.
陪我吃庆功宴
Wanzhen,
婉真
congratulations on your promotion.
升职快乐
Thanks.
谢谢老板
I know
我知道
your abilities go beyond this.
你的能力绝不止于此
Keep going!
加油
I'm so touched.
太让我感动了
Keep it up.
加油 加油
Keep making money for you.
加油为你赚钱
That's what I like to hear.
这话我爱听
Keep going and make money for me!
加油 为我赚钱
You still have something for me?
还有啊
What's this?
这什么呀
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
What a coincidence!
这么巧啊
Yes, I…
对 我
I was just downstairs getting a package.
我 我刚好下楼拿快递
The flowers are pretty.
花挺漂亮的
Mom.
妈妈
Wanwan, Zhenzhen,
婉婉 真真
slow down.
慢点 慢点
Dear,
宝贝
be careful.
小心啊
Mom, what's this?
妈妈 这个是什么
Flowers and gifts?
鲜花还有礼物
These are Mommy's prizes
这是妈妈今天的
for promotion.
升职奖品
Want them?
送给你们好不好
Sure!
好
Here you go.
来
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you, Mommy!
谢谢妈妈
Sister,
姐
do I look ugly now?
我现在是不是变丑了
I didn't give you a plastic surgery.
我没给你整容啊
You look great!
好看的
Look, your skin is so good now,
你看你现在多好呀
no pores,
也没有毛孔
no wrinkles.
也没有皱纹
Do you know why?
知道为什么吗
Estrogen.
雌激素
You're beautiful.
很美的
You're just saying that to comfort me.
你哄我
Well, I'm happy to do that.
那我愿意哄你啊
How do you feel
怎么样啊
after having
你这生完了二胎
your second child?
有什么新感受啊
Looking for some tips?
想跟我取经啊
Aren't I just following in your footsteps?
我这不走你后头了吗
Is there ever a time
你还有走我
when you're behind me?
后头的时候哪
So happy!
好开心啊
You feel incredibly satisfied,
内心得到了
don't you?
极大满足是吗
Immensely.
相当满足
Alright,
那行
go on.
说吧
Got another scar.
多了一道疤
Can't get over it, can you?
咱这事是不是过不去了
How about this:
那要不然这样
I'll have a Caesarean too.
我也剖腹产
Fine,
行
I'll make my brother-in-law
我让姐夫在
sign the consent form.
手术同意书上签字
No need.
不用
You just sign it.
就你签
Revenge needs
报复嘛
to be ruthless.
就得狠一点
Got it.
可以
Can we move on now?
过去了吧
Sister,
姐
do you think
你说我今后
I won't be able to do anything from now on?
是不是什么事都干不了
What do you mean?
什么意思呀
Ever since I had Xiongxiong,
你说我生了熊熊之后
I haven't worked a day
这么多年了
in years,
一天班都没上过
and now with Little Watermelon,
这现在又多了个小西瓜
I feel like I'll never
我是不是以后
be able to do
什么自己想干的事
what I want again.
都干不了了
What do you want to do?
那你想干什么呢
I'm not sure,
我也说不好
but I feel
但我就是觉得
less like myself every day.
越来越不像我自己了
I think you don't have
我觉得吧
to worry about it.
你就是想多了
Plenty of white-collar
那 我们这些白领
workers
上班的
have two or three kids,
有好多二胎三胎的呢
and they're still
人家不是一样
doing their own things.
也能干自己的事吗
Nothing stops them, right?
啥也没耽误啊
Still watching movies with their husbands,
同样还是跟老公看电影
having late-night snacks with colleagues.
跟同事吃消夜
As long as you plan
只要你合理地安排好
your time and life well,
你的时间和生活
you can do whatever you want.
想做什么都是可以的
Just think about Wanzhen.
你看你婉真姐
She had two kids from the start.
人从一开始就带俩孩子
Did it delay anything for her?
耽误啥了
Exactly,
是
then she got divorced.
然后离婚了
I think it was
那我觉得是
because Yu Hai was unreliable.
于海他不靠谱
Who's more dependable
你们家贾浩文
than Jia Haowen?
还有比他更靠谱的吗
Honestly,
我说实话啊
sometimes I feel like
有时候我都觉得
even Li Lin is not as good
我们家李临
as Jia Haowen.
不如你们家贾浩文的
Are you jealous of me?
你嫉妒我了 是吗
Yeah.
嫉妒啊
Mixed with a bit of envy.
还夹杂着羡慕
Just relax
你呀
and take care of yourself.
你就好好的吧
You're just going
你现在就是
through a special period right now.
一个特殊时期
It's natural to be a bit sensitive.
可能呢 会敏感一些
But don't worry.
但是没关系的
I'm here to get through it with you.
姐陪你一起熬着呗
When you decide what you want to do,
回头等你想干啥了
just let me know.
跟姐说
Okay?
对吧
I'll help you arrange it.
姐帮你安排
Can't trust my abilities?
姐这能力你还信不过吗
Right?
是不是
Here you go again,
又来了
trying to comfort me.
你又开始哄我
Sis,
姐
I know.
其实我都知道
You've been trying to cheer me up.
你一从进门就开始哄我
If I were an actress,
我要是个演员
you wouldn't even notice, would you?
是不是你就看不出来啦
No chance.
没机会了
But I like it.
但是我喜欢
I'm happy to let you comfort me.
我愿意让你哄
It makes me happy.
我高兴
Then I'll keep doing it,
那就哄你
comforting you for the rest of your life,
这辈子都哄着你
okay?
好不
You said it!
你说的啊
When have I ever kept my word?
姐什么时候说话算数过
Here, have some apple.
来 吃苹果
You cut it so big!
你切那么大
My mouth is too small to eat that.
我嘴那么小 怎么吃呀
Then I'll chop it into a puree for you.
那我给它剁成泥啊
Haowen just cuts a little piece.
浩文就切那么一点
Now you realize how good your husband is.
这时候知道你老公好了
Don't act up anymore, okay?
以后别再作了啊
I'm really getting more impressed
我真是越来越佩服
with Jia Haowen.
你们家贾浩文了
I really mean that.
真的
Alright.
这样可以了
Is it okay?
可以吧
Yeah.
可以
So sweet.
好甜啊
Some women are princesses before marriage
人家结婚前当公主
and after marriage, they're just discarded.
结婚后当糟粕
But you're still a princess
你这结婚之后
even after getting married,
也是个公主啊
you're never satisfied, always acting up.
还老不知足 天天作
Don't do that anymore, okay?
以后别作了啊
Just pamper me in the future, okay?
以后哄着点我啊
Yunjie,
云阶
I'm going to pick up your mom.
我去接你妈妈
You have dinner with your aunt tonight.
晚上你就跟大姑吃饭
Don't wait for us.
不用等我们
Yunjie,
云阶
I'm talking to you.
我跟你说话呢
What are you looking at?
你看什么呢
It's washed.
洗了
This pair of jeans is finally washed.
这条牛仔裤终于被洗了
Great!
太好了
What do you know?
你懂什么呀
I was nurturing them for three months
我这养了三个月的形儿
to get the shape just right.
这终于出来点了
Aunt washed them all.
这被我大姑全洗了
Aunt didn't know
你大姑又不知道
you were taking care of your jeans,
你在养牛仔裤
right?
是吧
Where did you leave them?
那你 你放哪儿了
On the balcony in my room.
就我那屋阳台上呀
Yeah,
对啊
worn jeans just
穿过的裤子
tossed on the balcony.
就这样扔在阳台上面
Who wouldn't want to wash them?
谁见到它不想洗啊
Didn't dad wash them
爸爸是不是之前
once before?
也给你洗过一回
Now, this is the second time.
这不第二次了吗
Well,
那
maybe the third time
万一第三次的形儿
will turn out even better.
比这次更好呢
Alright.
没事了 没事了
Never mind.
好了
Turn
向后转
around
不看牛仔裤了
and go do your homework.
做作业去
Where are you going?
你这干吗去啊
To pick up Meng'an.
接梦安啊
She's at the postpartum center
她不是在月子中心
with Mengxin.
陪着梦心嘛
I was going to tell you,
我就想跟你说呀
Meng'an has been pregnant
这梦安不是怀孕
for several months now.
好几个月了吗
She's 40, it's not easy
四十岁了
to be pregnant.
怀个孩子不容易
She almost had
原来
a miscarriage before,
她不还有
remember?
先兆性流产呢吗
Don't let her run around too much.
你别让她总跑来跑去的
She needs more rest.
多休息
Got it, sis.
知道了 姐
Now,
这不现在
Mengxin is a bit down
梦心生完之后
after giving birth,
心里面有点不痛快吗
and Meng'an is the only one
除了梦安
who can comfort her.
那她谁的话都不听
She only listens to her sister
她就听她姐的
and loves to talk to her.
就爱跟她姐说说话
How come she always listens
人家
to her sister,
怎么都能听人家姐的
but you don't listen to yours?
你咋不听呢
Have I not listened to you?
我还不听啊
How else can I listen to you?
我还要怎么听你的呀
I listen to you for everything.
我什么都听你的了
If you had listened to me earlier,
你要是早听你姐的
your second child would've grown up.
那二胎都满地跑了
Yeah.
是是 是是是
Third and fourth ones would follow.
三胎四胎跟着走呢
So happy.
开心啊
Sis,
姐
if we have clothes to be washed,
我们家要洗的衣服
they should be in the laundry basket.
它一定是放在洗衣篓里
If they're scattered
它要是不在洗衣篓里
elsewhere,
散布在其他的地方
there must be a reason.
一定是有它的道理的
What do you mean?
什么意思
Did you wash
你是不是把
Yunjie's jeans?
云阶那条牛仔裤给洗了
They were too dirty,
太脏了
and the water turned black.
那水都是黑的
Yeah.
是
The black water is
就是那个黑水啊
what she was nurturing.
她养的
It's her pride and joy.
她的心血啊
You washed it.
你给她洗了
and she's heartbroken.
她挺心疼的
What?
这这 这
She was nurturing them?
这 她养的
Yeah,
对
it's part
这 这就是孩子们的
of her
这个追求
aesthetic pursuit.
美学追求
It's fine.
行 我知道了
I'll explain
我一会儿啊
to Yunjie.
跟云阶说一声
Never mind. I've already talked to her.
不用了 我跟她说过了
I'll just tell her
我跟她说一下
to put any clothes
以后要洗的衣服
that need washing
她就放在那衣篓里
in the laundry basket,
是吧
not scattered around.
别乱放
You carry on with your work.
你忙吧
Why would she
这牛仔裤
nurture jeans?
她为什么还要养呢
I've heard of flowers,
这养花
but jeans?
养泥儿
Never heard
没听说过呀
of that.
这 这 这
You've reconciled with Mengxin.
跟梦心和好了
That's one worry less.
了却了心头一件大事
That's good.
那就好
How's work?
工作上怎么样
Getting along with the new deputy director?
那新来的副总监
Is he good at his job?
用得还得手吧
Yeah.
得手得很呢
You know who it is?
你知道这人是谁吗
Who?
谁啊
Huang Sisi.
黄思思
Huang...
黄
She's with Yu Hai...
就是和于海
What a coincidence.
这么巧啊
Such a small circle.
你们这个圈子好小哦
Mr. Zhang.
张总
Meng'an,
梦安哪
take a look
你快看黄思思那个
at the short video
发的那个短视频
Huang Sisi posted.
你赶紧看
What happened?
怎么了
Something wrong?
出事了
No.
什么呀
It's gone viral!
火了
Did you see it?
看见了吗
I was watching it all along.
我一直关注着呢
In just a few hours,
才上线几个小时
it's gotten over 100,000 views.
流量就破十万加了
Huang Sisi is really good.
黄思思还是很厉害的
I'll tell you that.
我跟你说
A new broom sweeps clean,
新官上任三把火
bringing us a lot
这给我们引流了不少
of new users.
新的用户
Yeah.
知道吗
That's something to celebrate!
那也是值得恭喜的呀
Congratulations, Mr. Zhang!
恭喜啊 张总
Okay.
好
Bye.
再见
He sent a red packet in the group chat.
张总在群里发红包呢
Feeling a bit uncomfortable about it?
心里有点不舒服是吧
Not really,
那倒也没有
but I'm definitely
但肯定没那么痛快
not quite happy with it.
就是了
So, should I take this red packet or not?
你说这红包我抢吗
Take it.
抢
You absolutely must take it.
必须得抢
And not just take it,
不光要抢
you should be the first to do so.
还得带头抢
Don't miss a single one.
一个都不能落下
Why?
为什么呀
Because you're the boss.
你是领导啊
When new colleagues achieve something,
新来的同志有成绩了
you need to lead
你得带头表示鼓励
by showing support.
是吧
It makes you seem generous
这显得自己 大气
and approachable.
平易近人
You're so smart.
智慧啊
That's exactly
要不说我怎么就
why I like you.
看上你了呢
Didn't you say
你不是说
it was my face you liked?
看上的是我这张脸吗
Yeah,
对呀
because whenever I see your face,
我看着你这张脸
I just can't stay mad.
我就发不起脾气
What's that supposed to mean?
什么意思
So cheesy?
肉麻哪
It's kind of exciting.
有点小激动
Sis, we're back!
姐 我们回来了
Do you know what time it is?
都几点了
You're a high-risk pregnant woman
你一个高龄孕妇
coming home so late every day.
每天回来这么晚
Do you think that's appropriate?
你觉得合适吗
And you,
还有你
picking her up
你去接人了
takes so much time.
还接这么晚回来
What kind of husband are you?
你像个做丈夫的吗
It's my fault.
我的问题
I know
对对对
it's out of line.
不像话 不像话
Sis.
姐
it's a good thing you're here at home,
还好家里边有你
otherwise,
要不然的话
we wouldn't know
我们真不知道
what to do.
该怎么办呢
Thank you so much, sis!
辛苦了啊 姐
Alright.
好了 好了
Good girl.
乖
Be good
下次
next time.
听话啊
From now on,
以后
Be home before 7 PM.
每天回来不能超过七点
Got it.
知道啦
Now, let's check your blood pressure.
来 量血压
Check it.
量
Check it right away.
马上量
Sis, you have no idea that
姐 你都不知道
registering is such a hassle.
现在 建个档可麻烦了
They want us to go to the community clinic,
让我们去什么社区门诊
then the street office.
还要去街道办事处
Yeah.
对
Just thinking about it gives me a headache.
想想就头疼
Don't worry.
不用头疼
I'll handle it.
我去办
I'll go.
我去
Give me the materials.
把资料给我
I'll take care of it.
我去办
You?
你去办
Will you even know the way?
你知道怎么走啊
Don't you know me by now?
你还不了解你姐
On this planet,
这地球上
just give me an address,
只要你给我个地址
and there's nowhere I can't find!
哪有我找不着的呀
Besides,
再说了
our family runs a clinic
咱们家是开诊所的
and I know
那流程
the procedures.
我熟
Alright,
好
we'll leave it to you.
那就辛苦姐了啊
Your blood sugar
你这个
is a bit high,
血糖有一点偏高
and your cholesterol too.
血脂有点偏高
From tomorrow,
从明天开始啊
let's control your diet.
咱们饮食控制
Pack lunch.
带饭
Hmmm.
就是
Sis,
姐
you're pretty good
你从这个
at checking blood pressure
医务岗位上退休之后
even after retiring
量血压应该
from the medical field.
可以啊
Sis.
姐
It's a bit high.
有一点高
Should we check it again?
要不你 你再量一回
I'll calm down a bit.
我 我平静一下
Alright,
好
calm
那你啊
your mind,
心里平静一下啊
and don't think about unpleasant things.
别想不愉快的事
Let's try again.
好吧 我们再量一下
Hey,
各位
it's almost 10 PM.
快十点了
No talking.
别说话
Let's check it again.
来 再量一下
You're enjoying this, huh?
过瘾啊你
Blood pressure is serious business.
那血压是大事
What do you know?
你懂什么啊
Sis, It's enough.
行了 姐
It's too tight,
太 太紧
Can't take it anymore.
姐 受不了
Have
你
you released the air or not?
你放气了没有啊
It's still a bit high.
还是有点高
Pack lunch.
带饭
Thank you, Dr. Li.
谢谢李大夫
So kind of you.
真好
Even take care of the meal.
还管饭
Sis.
姐
Why aren't you asleep yet?
你 你咋还没睡哪
I suddenly thought of something.
我就突然想起个事来
What is it?
你说
I wanted to ask
就是我想问问
about the effectiveness
那个药的疗效
of that medicine.
它怎么样啊
Let me tell you,
我跟你说呀
with Chinese medicine,
中医
it's all about regulation.
它都是调理的
It takes time.
就是时间比较长
Today,
我今天
when I coaxed Mengxin to take the medicine,
哄心心喝药的时候
I told her it would relieve symptoms
跟她说的是
in one dose
一副有缓解
and be effective in seven days.
七天见疗效
Seven days?
七天
She already thinks that's too slow.
这她还嫌慢呢
Then…
那
Let me call
那那 我赶紧给你姐夫
your brother-in-law.
打个电话
Coming.
来了 来了
I will handle it.
来来来 给我
Mom.
妈
Yeah.
来
She's asleep.
睡着了 睡着了
Alright.
好的 好的 行
Don't worry.
好好好 放心放心
Take care.
您慢点啊
Honey,
媳妇
we're home!
到家了
It's been a while and you must miss home.
好久没回来 想家了吧
Let's go.
走走走 快
Why are we here?
怎么回这儿了
Aren't we going to your parents' house?
不是去父母家吗
Dad is still recovering,
爸不是康复呢吗
Mom's struggling alone.
妈一个人照顾不来
Honey,
宝宝
come on.
来来来
Let me help you.
我搀着你
We're home!
回家了
Let's go.
快快快
Honey.
媳妇
I'll help.
扶着啊
We're home.
回家
Madam is back.
太太回来了
I'll help.
来 我扶 我扶
Let me help. You go get the luggage.
我来扶 你快去拿行李
Let's go.
快快快
I'll help you.
我来帮你
What's in Mengxin's suitcase?
梦心这箱子里装的啥呀
Why is it so heavy?
咋这么沉呢
Lacking exercise?
怎么 缺乏锻炼了
Mrs. Jia's postpartum recovery
贾总太太这月子坐了
is almost two months now.
都快两个月了
You've been lounging at home all day
你天天在家闲着
and still getting paid,
还领着工资
time to do some work.
干点活吧
Help me,
你一会儿帮我
help me hold this for a moment.
帮我拿一下啊
Where's my cooler box?
我的那个保温箱呢
Madam.
阿姨
It's here.
在这儿
Here.
这个 这个
This is my granddaughter's food.
这可是我孙女的口粮
I need to get it in the fridge quickly.
我赶快给她冰起来
Baby,
宝宝
such a good girl.
好乖呀
So pretty.
好美哦
Drink mommy's milk.
吃妈妈的奶奶哦
White and beautiful.
长得又白又漂亮
The whole family is
吃 吃 吃
trying to get me to lactate.
全家人都哄着让我下奶
So annoying.
烦死了
So beautiful.
好美哦
Where's my luggage?
我行李呢
Luggage?
行李
Oops, quiet down.
这撞的 小点声
I'll get it.
我来 我来 我来
Don't move.
别动 别动
Move aside, I've got it.
走开 我来
Almost feeding time.
马上吃奶奶了
Pack it up nicely.
收拾好
Be quiet.
轻点
Avoid her hysterical screams.
别让她又歇斯底里地喊
What's up?
什么事
Is your wife recovered, Mr. Jia?
贾总 嫂子出月子了吗
I just got home.
我刚到家
Well, Mr. Jia,
那贾总
can you come to the office now?
您现在能来公司了吧
Why would I come?
来什么来啊 你
I haven't even unpacked yet.
我这行李还没收拾呢
The chairman is here today.
董事长今天来了
You'd better come over,
您赶紧来吧
or you'll be in trouble.
再不来 说不过去了啊
If he's here, he's here.
他来就来呗
She doesn't know how to care for the baby.
你嫂子不会带孩子
I still have
我一会儿还得去
to go pick up my eldest child.
接老大呢
You should still come over.
您还是来一趟吧
Work is important.
工作要紧
Fine.
行行行 行
You are so annoying!
你们烦不烦
You're driving me crazy!
你们简直是烦死啦
Jia Haowen, does he think
这个贾浩文
he's the one having the baby?
孩子是他自己在生吗
Mr. Zheng,
那 郑董
Mr. Jia is on his way.
贾总这不马上就来了吗
He's always absent when I'm in the office.
我回回来公司他都不在
My attendance is higher than his.
我的出勤率比他还高
At this rate,
这样下去
does he still want
他这个总经理
to keep his job as general manager?
他还想不想干了
Hurry
你快把她的
and sort out
小衣服小毛巾
her little clothes and towels.
都弄整齐了
Don't let her
别让那奶奶
start screaming at me again.
又跟我歇斯底里
I'm heading out for a bit.
我出去一下
I'll be back soon.
马上回来啊
Where are you going?
你去哪儿啊
Something came up at work.
公司有事
I'll be back soon.
我马上回来啊
If you leave,
你走了 我一个人
How do I handle the baby alone?
怎么弄孩子啊
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
Honey,
姑奶奶
I'll be right back!
我马上就回来
Sweetheart.
宝贝
Don't come back!
你别回来了
What are you staring at?
你看着我干吗
Move these things downstairs.
把东西搬下去
Morning, everyone.
大家早
Good morning, Ms. Xu.
许总监早
Get ready,
准备好啊
something big is happening today!
今天要卷起来啦
What?
又卷啊
The project Huang Sisi brought in
黄思思带来那项目
has been going full speed for two months,
大干了两个月
and it's wrapping up today.
今天要收尾了
I even saw her
我都看见
bringing cake to celebrate.
她买蛋糕准备庆祝了
So, should I eat the cake or not?
那你说这蛋糕我还吃吗
Of course, you should eat it.
必须吃啊
Don't let your spirit waver.
卷不过 气势不能输
Besides,
再说了
you're her superior.
你是她上级
If you don't eat,
你要不吃
people might think
大家会觉得
you have an issue with her.
你对她有意见
Why does it feel worse
怎么觉着比吞了苍蝇
than swallowing a fly?
还难受啊
Swallowing flies is part of the workplace.
职场里都吞苍蝇
Not big a deal.
正常
You need
你这精神头
to put on a strong face, okay?
可得给我打起来啊
Everyone, pause for a moment.
大家先别忙了
Treat
快招呼内容部的
the Content Department.
小伙伴们
Have some cake.
吃蛋糕了
Here comes the fly.
苍蝇来了
Coffee and milk tea
等一下还有咖啡奶茶
will be here soon.
送来给大家
Let's celebrate the success
庆祝一下我来到新苗
of my first project at Xinmiao Media.
第一个项目的成功
Come on.
来 快快快
Thank you, Ms. Huang.
谢谢黄总监
Thanks.
谢谢
Forks!
叉子 叉子
Look
你看看
at all your subordinates.
就你这些下属
Who isn't swallowing flies here?
哪个不吞苍蝇啊
Swallow them gracefully.
你得吞得比他们还漂亮
It's only been a short time,
这才来多久
and already a big hit.
就做了个大爆款
Congratulations.
恭喜啊
Share the joy.
分享喜悦
Thanks.
谢谢
Let's go.
走
Who else hasn't gotten any yet?
还有谁没有拿的
Two directors, have some cake.
来 两位总监吃蛋糕
Ms. Xu,
许总监
your Content Department
你们内容部真的是
is really good!
后生可畏啊
Our Content Department
我们内容部
doesn't have a single softie,
就没一个吃素的
right?
是吧
Ms. Huang.
黄总监
Congratulations!
恭喜啊
Thank you, Ms. Xu, for the recognition.
谢谢许总监肯定
I'll keep working hard.
我会继续努力的
Great!
好
Have some cake.
拿蛋糕啊
Alright.
来 吃
Thanks.
谢谢啊
After you finish the cake,
等会儿大家吃完了
let's have a meeting
咱们开个会吧
to review
复盘一下
the previous successes
总结一下之前的成绩
and plan
然后再制定一下
for the future.
未来的计划
Ms. Huang,
黄总监
this is your grand entrance
这是你在新苗的
at Xinmiao Media.
开门红啊
We have to hold on
这个胜利果实
to this victory.
我们要保持住啊
By the way,
正好
I need to talk to you
我要找您汇报一下
about my future work plans.
我未来的工作规划
Alright.
好
You all carry on!
行 那你们先忙啊
It's delicious.
好吃
So sweet.
真甜哪
Where did you get it?
哪儿买的
If you want more, just let me know,
想吃啊 随时呼我
I'll get plenty.
管够
No.
那不行
It's not the same when you buy it
你买的 跟我自己买的
versus when I buy it myself.
味道还是不一样的
Madam,
太太
what's this thing for?
这个是干什么用的
It's a breast pump.
吸奶器啊
Didn't I ask you
我不是让你学学
to learn about childcare?
怎么育儿吗
You don't even know this?
你这个都不知道
How will you take care of the baby?
怎么带孩子啊
I've talked to Ms. Li Jing
我跟李静大姐都问过了
what to prepare.
该准备些什么
I know how to raise a child.
带孩子我还是会的
I brought up
我们家孩子
my kids by myself.
就是我自己带的
Madam,
太 太太
I've prepared the diapers,
我 我准备了 纸尿裤
wet wipes, dry tissues,
湿纸巾 干纸巾
soft wipes, disinfectant,
柔湿巾 消毒液
and I've sewn a quilt for the baby.
还给孩子缝了小被子
Also, there's the bed guard.
还有那个床围子
Madam,
那个
all these high-tech things…
太太 你这些高科技
I've never seen them before.
我以前都没见过
Back then when I had kids,
我们那时候生孩子
we didn't have all these nice things.
没有这么多好东西的
Ying,
英子姐
for everything the baby needs,
所有孩子用的东西呢
just buy another set
你按照我准备的这些
according to what I've prepared,
再买一套
alright?
好吧
The brand is different.
品牌不一样
Oh, by the way,
对了
have you bought the sterilizer yet?
消毒柜买了没有
No, I haven't bought the sterilizer,
消毒柜没买
but I did get
但是我买了那个
disinfectant and disinfectant wipes.
消毒水跟消毒纸巾
No, that won't do.
不行
You have to use a proper sterilizer.
要用专业的消毒柜
Chemical substances can
化学成分会刺激
irritate the baby's skin.
小孩的皮肤
Then I'll buy one.
那我去买啊
Oh, madam,
太太
I have rhinitis.
我是鼻炎
It's not contagious.
不传染的
Alright,
行行行
I'll buy the sterilizer myself.
那个 消毒柜我自己买
Disinfect all
这些瓶瓶罐罐
these bottles and jars again,
我拿出来的
okay?
重新消毒一下啊
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜
such a sweet baby.
好宝贝
You are so beautiful!
你长得真漂亮啊
Look at those big eyes,
你看那大眼睛
they're so lovely.
真好看哪
Such a
好宝贝
good baby,
好乖哦
Grandma loves you so much.
奶奶好喜欢你啊
Mom.
妈
That's great.
真棒
Baby.
宝贝
What's up?
啥事
Ying isn't suitable.
那个 小英姐不行啊
We need to find an infants' nurse.
要找一个育儿嫂
There's no need.
不用了吧
Aren't I here?
这不有我呢吗
I'm specifically here
我就是专门来
to help you take care of the baby.
给你们带孩子的
Right, Little Watermelon?
是不是 小西瓜
You can just lend a hand.
您搭把手就行了
If I make you tired,
我要再把您累着了
the responsibility would be too much.
责任就太大了
Nannies are quite expensive, you know.
育儿嫂挺贵的
And with two nannies
你说咱们家
at home,
还请两个保姆
isn't that too extravagant?
是不是太破费了
Isn't it?
是不是啊
Alright,
行
then we won't hire one.
那不找啦
That's more like it.
这就对啦
She's my granddaughter.
我亲孙女儿
Leaving her with anyone, I'd be uneasy.
我交给谁看我也不放心
Let Mr. Jia come back
让老贾回来带
and take care of his own daughter.
带他亲女儿
No more working.
别上班了
Then…
那那
Find someone immediately.
找找找
find someone immediately.
马上找啊 找
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜
your mom wants
你妈妈又要给你
to find another nanny to take care of you
找个育儿嫂啦
together with grandma,
跟奶奶一起看着你
how does that sound?
好不好啊
Look at Little Watermelon,
你看我们小西瓜
drinking mommy's milk
吃妈妈的奶
is really different.
就是不一样啊
Those rosy cheeks.
这小脸蛋红扑扑的
Breastfeeding is just so good,
这母乳喂养就是好
right?
对不对
Our precious little one
我们的宝贝呀
is growing up so healthy
长得可真好
and strong.
真健康啊
Such a good baby.
真是好宝贝
Grandma loves you so much.
奶奶好喜欢你哦